mku.com 2008-05-09

# MKU :: MKU Privacy Policy, MKU Privacy Statement, Privacy Statement, Privacy Policy

|  |  |  |    
---|---|---  
| **MKU - PRIVACY STATEMENT** |    
|  |    
| 

The website you have entered is operated by MKU ("MKU"). The privacy statement below covers the site www.mku.com. MKU is committed to protecting your personal privacy. This Privacy Policy outlines the types of information that are collected by MKU on its website, and how we use and protect it. This Policy also explains the choices that you can make about the way your information is collected and used. This Policy applies only to www.mku.com, and it does not apply to banners, sweepstakes and other advertisements or promotions that we may sponsor or participate in on web sites owned by third parties.

|   
|  |    
| **Information Collection and Use** |    
|  |    
| 

**Information Collection**  
MKU is the sole owner of the information collected on www.mku.com. MKU collects Personal Information from users at several points on our web site.   
As used in this Privacy Policy, "Personal Information" means any information that is linked to User's identity such as Name, Address, Telephone number and Email address etc.

|    
|  |    
| 

**Enquiry**  
We request information from the user on our enquiry form. A user must provide contact information (such as name, email, address etc.). This information is used for mailing purposes, to fulfill customer's enquiry and to contact when required.

|    
|  |    
| 

**Information Use**  
Information is collected and used primarily for the purpose of replying to customer's enquiry. In addition to the primary purposes for which personal information is collected, we may use the personal information to contact a user to confirm information related to a purchase order.

|    
|  |    
| We may also use User's information for: 

  * Our internal surveys to obtain feedback on our product, services, our web site, or on other aspects of our business that impact you as a MKU customer;
  * To promote other products and services that we think may be of User's interest;
  * To send promotional materials;
  * To provide our free email newsletters;

|    
|  |    
| 

**Profile**  
We store information that we collect through cookies, log files, clear gifs, and/or third parties to create a profile of our users. A profile is stored information that we keep on individual users that details their viewing preferences. Consequently, collected information is tied to the users personally identifiable information to provide offers and improve the content of the site for the user. This profile is used to tailor a user's visit to our Web site, and to direct pertinent marketing promotions to them. We do not share your profile with other third parties.

|    
|  |    
| 

**Log Files**  
Like most standard Web site servers we use log files. This includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses, etc. are not linked to personally identifiable information. IP addresses are tied to personally identifiable information to enable our Web-based service. We use Web analytics software called URCHIN that uses log files to analyze user movement.

|    
|  |    
| 

**Clear Gifs (Web Beacons/Web Bugs)**   
We employ a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails the recipients have opened. Clear gifs are tiny graphics about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. Clear gifs are tied to users' personally identifiable information. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. If users would like to opt-out of these emails, please see the Opt-out section.

|    
|  |    
| **Communications from the Site** |    
|   |    
| 

Special Offers and Updates   
Members will occasionally receive information on products, services, special deals, and newsletters. Out of respect for the privacy of our users we provide the option to not receive these types of communications. Please see the Choice and Opt-out sections.

|    
|  |    
| 

Newsletter   
If a user wishes to subscribe to our newsletter, we ask for contact information such as name and email address. Out of respect for our users privacy we provide a way to opt-out of these communications. Please see the Choice and Opt-out sections.

|    
|  |    
| 

Service Announcements   
On rare occasions it is necessary to send out a strictly service related announcements. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance we might send users an email. Generally, users may not opt-out of these communications, though they can deactivate their account. However, these communications are not promotional in nature. Users may opt-out of these communications. Please see our Choice and Opt-out section.

|    
|  |    
| **Sharing**   
|    
|   |    
| 

Legal Disclaimer   
Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on our Web site.

|    
|  |    
| 

Aggregate Information (non-personally identifiable)   
We share aggregated demographic information with our partners and advertisers. This is not linked to any personally identifiable information.

|    
|  |    
| 

Third Party Advertisers   
MKU shares Web site usage information about users with a reputable third party 'Torrocks Brand Communications' (Torrocks) and its Technical Partner 'GeoRapid India Pvt. Ltd.' (GeoRapid) for the purpose of targeting our Internet banner advertisements on other web sites.

|    
|  |    
| 

Service Providers   
We partner with other third parties [Torrocks and GeoRapid] to provide specific services. [For example, Direct Mailing campaigns both postal mails and e-Mails] When the user signs up for these particular services, we share names, or other contact information that is necessary for the third party to provide these services. These third parties are not allowed to use personally identifiable information except for the purpose of providing these services.

|    
|  |    
| 

Business Transitions   
In the event MKU goes through a business transition, such as a merger, being acquired by another company, or selling a portion of its assets, users' personal information will, in most instances, be part of the assets transferred, users will be notified via email/postal mail and a prominent notice on our Web site for 30 days prior to a change of ownership or control of their personal information. If as a result of the business transition, the users' personally identifiable information will be used in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection they will be given choice consistent with our notification of changes section.

|    
|  |    
| 

**Choice/Opt-out**  
Our users are given the opportunity to 'opt-out' of having their information used for purposes not directly related to our site at the point where we ask for information. For example, our order form has an 'opt-out' mechanism so users who buy a product from us, but don't want any marketing material, can keep their email address off of our lists.

Users who no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications may opt-out of receiving these communications by replying to unsubscribe in the subject line in the email or email us at protection@mku.com. We also offer an opt-out mechanism at the bottom of each Marketing campaign, OR the user may contact us by phone, e-Mail or Postal mail to opt-out.

|    
|  |    
| 

**Tell-A-Friend**  
If a user elects to use our referral service for informing a friend about our site / product, we ask them for the friend's name and email address. MKU will automatically send the friend an email inviting them to visit the site / informing about the product. MKU stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this email and tracking success of the referral program. The friend may contact MKU by replying to unsubscribe in the subject line in the email or email us at or use the opt-out mechanism at the bottom of the email to remove this protection@mku.com information from our database.

|    
|  |    
| **Security**  
This Web site takes every precaution to protect our users' information. When users submit sensitive information via the Web site, their information is protected both online and off-line. |    
|  |    
| 

We do everything in our power to protect user-information off-line. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job for example, our billing clerk, call-center or customer service representatives are granted access to personally identifiable information. Our employees must use password-protected screen-savers when they leave their desk. When they return, they must re-enter their password to re-gain access to user information. Furthermore, ALL employees are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy practices. Whenever new policies are added, our employees are notified and/or reminded about the importance we place on privacy, and what they can do to ensure our users' information is protected. Finally, the servers that store personally identifiable information are in a secure environment.

If users have any questions about the security at our Web site, users can send an email to protection@mku.com.

|    
|  |    
| 

**Supplementation of Information**  
In order for this Web site to properly fulfill its obligation to users it is necessary for us to supplement the information we receive with information from 3rd party sources.

We call User to verify his/her identity / address to make sure that the data provided by the user is correct. 

Enhancement of Marketing Profile  
We purchase third party marketing data and add it to our existing user database to better target our advertising and provide pertinent offers we think our users would be interested in. We use this information to enhance or overlay the 'profile' of individual users. This aggregate marketing data is therefore tied to the users' personally identifiable information.

**Correcting/Updating/Deleting/Deactivating Personal Information**  
If a user's personally identifiable information changes such as zip code, phone, email or postal address, or if a user no longer desires our service, we provide a way to correct, update or delete/deactivate users' personally identifiable information. This can usually be done at the Update profile page or by emailing our Customer Support at protection@mku.com Or, contact us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below.

**Notification of Changes**  
If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, and other places we deem appropriate so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected. 

If, however, we are going to use users' personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify users via email. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. However, if users have opted out of all communication with the site, or deleted/deactivated their account, then they will not be contacted, nor will their personal information be used in this new manner. In addition, if we make any material changes in our privacy practices that do not affect user information already stored in our database, we will post a prominent notice on our Web site notifying users of the change. In some cases where we post a notice we will also email users, who have opted to receive communications from us, notifying them of the changes in our privacy practices. 

**Contact Information**

If users have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us at:   
**  
MKU**  
103, Chandralok Complex  
26/72-D, Birhana Road  
Kanpur - 208 001, UP, INDIA  
Tel: (+91-512) 2363491  
Fax: (+91-512) 2354644  
Email: [protection@mku.com ](mailto:protection@mku.com)

|    
|  |
